Search [](# "Close Search")

Quick Links

#### Experiences

From hybrid workforces to smarter workspaces, bring together technology and touchpoints to deliver exceptional experiences.

Workforce

[

Hybrid Workforce

Enable teams with superior performance no matter the environment.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/hybrid-workforce/)[

Remote Workforce

Enable your workforce with the tools for success.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/remote-workforce/)

Workspace

[

Safe Environments

Protect and securely connect what matters most, regardless of location.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/safe-environments/)[

Smart Spaces

From contact tracing to footpath optimization, create the office of the future.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/smart-spaces/)

#### Technologies

Deliver exceptional experiences to people, places, and things with best-in-class Meraki technologies.

Platform

[

Platform

The cloud-first foundation for your entire network.](https://meraki.cisco.com/platform/)[

Meraki Dashboard

Monitor, manage, and optimize your network.](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/meraki-dashboard/)[

SASE

Converge networking and security stacks.](https://meraki.cisco.com/what-is/sase/)

Access Products

[

Wireless](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wi-fi/)[

Switching](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/switches/)[

Mobile Device Management](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/systems-manager/)

IoT Products

[

Smart Cameras](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/smart-cameras/)[

Sensors](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/sensors/)

Secure SD-WAN Products

[

Security and SD-WAN](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/security-sd-wan/)[

Digital Experience Assurance](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/digital-experience-assurance/)[

Hybrid Cloud](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/hybrid-cloud/)[

Unified SASE](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/cisco-plus-secure-connect/)[

Cellular Gateways](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wireless-wan/)

#### Touchpoints

Think beyond endpoint devices to all the people, places, and things connecting with the web.

  Industries

[

Financial Services](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/financial-services/)[

Manufacturing](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/manufacturing/)[

Local Government](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/government/)[

Federal Government](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/federal-government/)[

Primary Education](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/primary-education/)[

Healthcare](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/healthcare/)[

Retail](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/retail/)[

Higher Education](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/higher-education/)[

Small Business](https://meraki.cisco.com/small-business/)[

Hospitality](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/hospitality/)[

Physical Security](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/physical-security/)

#### Resources

Learn best practices, explore innovative solutions, and connect with others across the Meraki community.

Learn

[

Blog](https://meraki.cisco.com/blog/)[

Customer Stories](https://meraki.cisco.com/customers/)[

Documentation](https://documentation.meraki.com/)[

Product Catalog](https://meraki.cisco.com/product-catalog/)[

Resource Library](https://meraki.cisco.com/collateral/)[

Webinars](https://meraki.cisco.com/webinars/)

 Explore

[

Sustainability](https://meraki.cisco.com/about/sustainability/)[

Support](https://meraki.cisco.com/support)[

Wi-Fi 6E](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/next-gen-wifi/)[

Security](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/security-hub/)

Connect

[

App Marketplace](https://apps.meraki.io/)[

Community](https://community.meraki.com/)[

Developer Hub](https://developer.cisco.com/meraki/)[

Partners](https://meraki.cisco.com/partners/)[

Podcast](https://community.meraki.com/t5/Meraki-Unboxed-Podcast/bg-p/unboxed)

From hybrid workforces to smarter workspaces, bring together technology and touchpoints to deliver exceptional experiences.

Workforce

[

Hybrid Workforce

Enable teams with superior performance no matter the environment.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/hybrid-workforce/)[

Remote Workforce

Enable your workforce with the tools for success.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/remote-workforce/)

Workspace

[

Safe Environments

Protect and securely connect what matters most, regardless of location.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/safe-environments/)[

Smart Spaces

From contact tracing to footpath optimization, create the office of the future.](https://meraki.cisco.com/experiences/smart-spaces/)

Deliver exceptional experiences to people, places, and things with best-in-class Meraki technologies.

Platform

[

Platform

The cloud-first foundation for your entire network.](https://meraki.cisco.com/platform/)[

Meraki Dashboard

Monitor, manage, and optimize your network.](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/meraki-dashboard/)[

SASE

Converge networking and security stacks.](https://meraki.cisco.com/what-is/sase/)

Access Products

[

Wireless](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wi-fi/)[

Switching](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/switches/)[

Mobile Device Management](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/systems-manager/)

IoT Products

[

Smart Cameras](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/smart-cameras/)[

Sensors](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/sensors/)

Secure SD-WAN Products

[

Security and SD-WAN](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/security-sd-wan/)[

Digital Experience Assurance](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/digital-experience-assurance/)[

Hybrid Cloud](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/hybrid-cloud/)[

Unified SASE](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/cisco-plus-secure-connect/)[

Cellular Gateways](https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wireless-wan/)

Think beyond endpoint devices to all the people, places, and things connecting with the web.

  Industries

[

Financial Services](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/financial-services/)[

Manufacturing](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/manufacturing/)[

Local Government](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/government/)[

Federal Government](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/federal-government/)[

Primary Education](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/primary-education/)[

Healthcare](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/healthcare/)[

Retail](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/retail/)[

Higher Education](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/higher-education/)[

Small Business](https://meraki.cisco.com/small-business/)[

Hospitality](https://meraki.cisco.com/industries/hospitality/)[

Physical Security](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/physical-security/)

Learn best practices, explore innovative solutions, and connect with others across the Meraki community.

Learn

[

Blog](https://meraki.cisco.com/blog/)[

Customer Stories](https://meraki.cisco.com/customers/)[

Documentation](https://documentation.meraki.com/)[

Product Catalog](https://meraki.cisco.com/product-catalog/)[

Resource Library](https://meraki.cisco.com/collateral/)[

Webinars](https://meraki.cisco.com/webinars/)

 Explore

[

Sustainability](https://meraki.cisco.com/about/sustainability/)[

Support](https://meraki.cisco.com/support)[

Wi-Fi 6E](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/next-gen-wifi/)[

Security](https://meraki.cisco.com/solutions/security-hub/)

Connect

[

App Marketplace](https://apps.meraki.io/)[

Community](https://community.meraki.com/)[

Developer Hub](https://developer.cisco.com/meraki/)[

Partners](https://meraki.cisco.com/partners/)[

Podcast](https://community.meraki.com/t5/Meraki-Unboxed-Podcast/bg-p/unboxed)

Search [](#)

Quick Links

Meraki Support policy
=====================

Whether online, on the phone, or on-demand , our resources are available around the clock to ensure you are well supported from initial deployment to network growth

* **Policies**

[](javascript:void(0))Menu

Product End-of-Life (EOL) Policy
--------------------------------

* * *

Cisco Meraki may find it necessary to discontinue products and underlying firmware for a number of reasons, including product line enhancements, market demands, technology innovation, or the products simply mature over time and are replaced by functionally richer products. We have set our end-of-life (EOL) policy to help customers better manage their product end-of-life transition.

FOR HARDWARE:

When a product approaches its EOL, Cisco Meraki is committed to communicating important milestones throughout the EOL period.  These notifications will include the initial End of Sale (EOS) announcements, the official End of Sale (EOS) and End of Support (EOST) dates, as well as other key information pertaining to Cisco Meraki products.

Any products being discontinued will be announced as End of Sale and identified on the Cisco Meraki website typically up to six months prior to the EOS date (also known as the last order date). On the EOS Date, discontinued hardware products are removed from the price list and are no longer available for purchase. The device-specific licenses corresponding to discontinued hardware products will be available for purchase after the EOS Date unless the license(s) is/are listed in the “End-of-Life Products” list provided below. Cisco Meraki typically provides support for a given product for a period of five (5) years after the EOS date. If the discontinued product is not available for replacement or repair of an in-warranty return, Cisco Meraki may replace the discontinued product with functionally equivalent hardware and transfer the remaining license term from the replaced product to the replacement hardware.

Although legacy Cisco Meraki products typically can connect to our cloud-based management software for the entire useful life of the product, following the EOST Date, some things may change, including the following:

* Cisco Meraki cannot guarantee that legacy hardware products will be able to connect to the management software indefinitely following the EOST Date;
* Cisco Meraki Technical Support may no longer troubleshoot the legacy hardware products;
* Cisco Meraki may no longer issue firmware updates or patches for the legacy products; and
* New software features available for the management software may not be compatible with the legacy hardware functionality or with the firmware running on the legacy hardware.

If either of the first two situations above occurs, then we will use our best efforts to provide the customer with a workable solution for upgrading from the legacy hardware and, failing that, will credit the value of any remaining license time attributable to the legacy hardware to the customer’s Dashboard organization on a prorated basis.

Summary

* End-of-Sale Announcement: Date of official end-of-sales notice, typically six months prior to the last order date.
* End-of-Sale (EOS) Date: The last date to order the product through Cisco Meraki point-of-sale outlets. After this date, the product is no longer for sale via any Cisco Meraki authorized channel.
* End-of-Support (EOST) Date: The last date a product will be affirmatively supported by Cisco Meraki, typically five years following the EOS Date.

_\*Please note that announcements will be updated periodically to amend the functionally equivalent products._

For a full list of products, announcements, and dates, please refer to our [Meraki End-of-Life (EOL) Products and Dates documentation article](https://documentation.meraki.com/General_Administration/Other_Topics/Meraki_End-of-Life_(EOL)_Products_and_Dates).

In some limited cases, Cisco Meraki may also find it necessary to discontinue certain features.

FOR FIRMWARE:

To help our customers better manage their product end-of-life transition, Cisco Meraki aims to provide transparency with respect to key firmware lifecycle milestones. These milestones include the stable release date, firmware version restriction date, end of firmware maintenance date, and other key information pertaining to Cisco Meraki firmware. Definitions and descriptions of the terms referenced in the Product End of Life Milestones are included below.

* Stable Release: The most recent Cisco Meraki Recommended firmware version that has been made generally available in the Cisco Meraki Dashboard.
* Stable Release Date: The date on which the Stable Release is promoted and made generally available in the Cisco Meraki Dashboard.
* Vintage Firmware: Older versions of firmware made generally available prior to the latest Stable Release.
    * Engineering level support (e.g. patches, hotfixes, maintenance releases) will no longer be provided for Vintage Firmware. An update from these older versions may be required for troubleshooting purposes with Cisco Meraki Technical Support.
* End of Firmware Maintenance (EFM) Date: The date a firmware version will no longer be provided Engineering level support by Cisco Meraki.
    * The EFM Date typically aligns with the latest Stable Release Date and any firmware version that reaches the EFM Date will be considered Vintage Firmware.
* Firmware Version Restriction (FVR) Date: The date when legacy hardware will no longer be eligible for future firmware upgrades. After the FVR Date, Engineering level support, if available, will only be provided for critical security vulnerabilities until the hardware reaches its EOST date and when reported to Cisco Meraki Technical Support.

For any avoidance of doubt, access to Cisco Meraki Technical Support will continue to be provided with active licensing.

##### Product End-of-Life Milestones

_(Click the image to view larger)_ 

Cisco Meraki Warranties, Returns, and RMAs
------------------------------------------

* * *

Return policy terms may vary by region. Please refer to the Regional Return Policies section for region-specific terms.

##### Warranty

Cisco Meraki stands behind its products. Cisco represents to the first purchaser who purchased the Hardware from Cisco or a Cisco Partner that such Hardware will be free from material defects in materials and workmanship during the warranty period, as set forth below. The warranty period commences on the date the Hardware is shipped to that first purchaser. This warranty is non-transferable.

If Hardware does not meet this warranty, Cisco will, at its option, (a) repair, (b) replace, or (c) refund You the depreciated amount of the price You paid for such Hardware, calculated on a straight-line, five-year basis. All Hardware repaired or replaced by Cisco under this warranty will be warranted for the remainder of the warranty period referred to above. This Hardware warranty is subject to (y) Cisco Meraki’s Product End-of-Life (EOL) Policy, and (z) the liability provisions and warranty restrictions, limitations, and disclaimers of the Agreement.

The above warranty is Cisco’s sole liability and your sole remedy for Cisco’s breach of this Hardware warranty.

##### Warranty Periods

Cisco Meraki products come with the following warranty periods:

Product

Warranty Period

MS Products

Lifetime\*\*

MX Products

Lifetime\*\*

MR Indoor Products

Lifetime\*\*

MG Products

Lifetime\*\*

MR Outdoor Products

1 year

MT Indoor Products

3 year

MV Products (except MV21, MV71, and MV2)

5 year\*\*\*

Accessories\*

1 year

\*Original and replacement modular power supply units and fans for MS and MX Products included in lifetime warranty.

\*\*Product lifetime ends concurrently with product End-of-Support (EOST) Date as described in Cisco Meraki’s [End of Life (EOL) Policy](https://documentation.meraki.com/General_Administration/Other_Topics/Meraki_End-of-Life_(EOL)_Products_and_Dates).

\*\*\*Warranty period for MV21, MV71, and MV2 is 3 years.

##### Warranty Returns

If you are experiencing hardware issues, for any product under warranty (as described above), please contact Cisco Meraki support by logging in to dashboard (Help > Get help) or by [calling us](https://meraki.cisco.com/form/contact/).

To request a return materials authorization (RMA), please complete the [RMA request form in the Meraki dashboard](https://dashboard.meraki.com/rma). If your RMA request is approved, Cisco Meraki will email you an RMA number and a return shipping label free of charge. We will ship replacement units within five business days of receiving your defective units. If no trouble is found, we will contact you before taking further action.

If you require advance replacement, please call Cisco Meraki technical support. Unless you have purchased Cisco RMA Upgrade, advance replacement orders will ship within 1 business day on a best case effort basis.

Additional information about Cisco Meraki’s hardware warranty can be found in [Cisco Meraki’s End Customer Agreement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#end-customer-agreement).

##### Cisco RMA Upgrade

If you require replacement of Meraki products covered by [Cisco RMA Upgrade](https://meraki.cisco.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/meraki_now_solution_guide.pdf) services, please [call Meraki technical support](https://meraki.cisco.com/support/overview) and request Cisco RMA Upgrade advance replacement. Please include the Cisco RMA Upgrade service tier and affected device serial number (SN) with your request.

##### Product Trial Returns

If you would like to return units from a product trial, please go to your product trial webpage (using the link your rep provided you with) and go to the returns tab to fill out the RMA request form. If your trial hardware was shipped to the US, Canada, or an EU member country you will also be able to print out a return shipping label and ship the product back to Cisco Meraki at no charge to you.

##### Refund Requests

Effective January 30, 2022, all new Cisco and Meraki orders submitted for hardware, and any attached software, will be non-cancellable and cannot be modified starting 45 days prior to the current estimated ship date. Meraki license-only orders are not impacted by this policy. Non-cancellable orders are not eligible for RMA credit and are not eligible for an RMA exception. For additional information, please contact your Meraki representative.

To request a refund for your license-only order, please complete our RMA request form. All returns must meet the following criteria:

1. You purchased the product through an authorized Cisco Meraki reseller or directly from Cisco Meraki
2. You are the original purchaser of the product
3. You submit your refund request within 30 days of purchase
4. Your license is not a Meraki Subscription License\*

If your refund request is approved, Cisco Meraki will email you an RMA number and we will process your return. If you purchased through a Cisco Meraki reseller, your refund will be issued by that reseller. If you purchased directly from Cisco Meraki, we will issue a refund, typically within 15 days of processing the return. (If you paid by credit card we will credit the original credit card. If you paid by any other method, we will send you a check.)

Meraki Subscription Licensing refund criteria will remain the same as “license-only orders”; however, your refund will be prorated based on your Subscription Activation date. Please review cancellation policies and procedures in the Meraki Subscription [CCW Ordering Guide](https://salesconnect.cisco.com/Meraki/apex/scormanywhere__SCORM_Player?courseId=a1m8c00000qmvUFAAY)

##### Shipment Preparation

* Please return units in their entirety. That is, include all power supplies, antennas, and other components along with the original product box.
* Please use the original shipping carton and packaging material. If this is not possible, use another shipping carton with padding to protect the units from damage during shipping, and remove ALL inappropriate and/or inapplicable label(s). DO NOT ship a product without a carton.
* The customer will be charged for product that is damaged due to insufficient packaging.
* Once you have received your RMA number from Cisco Meraki via email, write this RMA number in large letters on the exterior of the shipping carton. Shipments to Cisco Meraki without an RMA approval will not be processed.
* If Cisco Meraki approves your RMA request, you will receive a confirmation email containing an RMA number within two business days. The address to which the product should be sent will also be included in that email.
* Cisco Meraki will provide a pre-paid return shipping label for warranty replacement return shipments. Cisco Meraki will also provide a pre-paid return shipping label for free trial return shipments from US (including Puerto Rico), any EU member country, Australia, Canada, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Indonesia, Japan, Mexico, New Zealand, Panama, Peru, the Philippines, Singapore, South Korea, Thailand, the United Arab Emirates, and the United Kingdom. For all other returns it is your responsibility to coordinate and pay for return shipping back to Cisco Meraki using the carrier of your choice. Cisco Meraki recommends that the return package has a tracking number and is insured for the proper value of its contents. Cisco Meraki is not responsible for packages lost by carriers.

##### Regional Return Policies

Online Privacy Statement
------------------------

* * *

Cisco Systems, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively “Cisco”) are committed to protecting your privacy and providing you with a positive experience on our websites and while using our products and services (“Solutions”).

This Privacy Statement applies to Cisco websites and Solutions that link to or reference this Privacy Statement and describes how we handle Personal Data and the choices available to you regarding collection, use, access, and how to update and correct your Personal Data. Additional information on our Personal Data practices with respect to Cisco Solutions may be provided in Solution specific [privacy data sheets and maps](https://trustportal.cisco.com/c/r/ctp/trust-portal.html?doctype=Privacy%20Data%20Map%7CPrivacy%20Data%20Sheet), offer descriptions, or other notices provided prior to or at the time of data collection. Certain Cisco websites and Solutions may have their own privacy documentation describing how we handle Personal Data for those websites or Solutions specifically. To the extent a specific notice for a website or Solution differs from this Privacy Statement, the specific notice will take precedent. If there is a difference in translated, non-English versions of this Privacy Statement, the U.S.-English version will take precedence.

##### What is Personal Data?

“Personal Data” is any information that can reasonably be used to identify an individual, or otherwise make an individual identifiable, and may include name, address, email address, phone number, login information (such as account number and password), social media account information, or payment card number.

The types of Personal Data we may process depend on the business context and the purposes for which it was collected. It may include:

* Contact, subscription, and account/registration details, as well as online identifiers
* Login credentials where we require an account be made
* Communications content (such as audio, video, text), social media and discussion forum, or other communications details when you interact with Cisco
* Financial Information (such as bank account details or credit card information)
* Details of an individual’s business and other interests and opinions (such as information held in a customer relationship management database)
* Information about the user and usage of our websites and Solutions, including System Information such as device identifiers and telemetry (such as IP or MAC address) when such data is linked or tied to a specific individual’s device

If we link other data with your Personal Data, we will treat that linked data as Personal Data.

##### Collection and use of your Personal Data

We may collect data, including Personal Data, about you as you use our websites and Solutions and interact with us. We also acquire Personal Data from trusted third-party sources and engage third parties to collect Personal Data on our behalf, in accordance with applicable laws.

We may use your Personal Data for the purposes of operating and helping to ensure the security of our business; delivering, improving, and customizing our websites and Solutions; sending notices, marketing, and other communications; and for other legitimate purposes permitted by applicable law.

We collect Personal Data for a variety of business reasons, such as:

* Customer relationship management and administration
* Order processing, including billing and payment
* Asset recovery and product returns and replacements
* Creating and managing user accounts
* Provisioning websites and Solutions and enabling the use of certain features
* Analyzing, personalizing, improving accuracy, and enhancing user experience, communications, and interactions
* Sending communications to you, including for marketing or customer satisfaction purposes, either directly from Cisco or from our partners
* Managing communications preferences. You can modify your communication preferences at any time. See [Your choices and selecting your communication preferences](#choices) below
* Contract performance, Solution delivery, and customer service
* Managing job applications
* Administering online education, testing, and certifications
* Facilitating conferences, webinars, and other events
* Protecting Cisco, our users, websites and Solutions, and others

If you choose to provide Cisco with a third party’s Personal Data (such as name, email, and phone number), you represent that you have the third party’s permission to do so. Examples include forwarding reference or marketing material to a friend or sending job referrals. Third parties may unsubscribe from any future communication following the link provided in the initial message or by submitting a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/).

In some instances, Cisco and the third parties we engage may automatically collect data through cookies, web logs, web beacons, and other similar applications. Please read the [Use of cookies and similar technologies](#cookies) section below for more information.

##### Your privacy rights

We need your help to keep your Personal Data accurate and up to date. We provide options to access, correct, suppress, or delete your Personal Data:

* You can view or edit your Cisco.com Personal Data and preferences online by using the [Cisco Profile Management Tool](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/account.html).
* When Cisco is acting as a “data controller,” you can exercise your rights of access and request corrections, suppression, objection, and deletion under applicable data protection laws directly with Cisco as described in the specific website and Solution documentation or by submitting a request through the [Privacy Request form](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/).
* When Cisco is acting as a “data processor,” and you wish to exercise your rights of access and request corrections, suppression, or deletion, Cisco will direct you to the data controller under the applicable data protection laws.
* If you need additional assistance, or help with accessing, correcting, suppressing, or deleting your Personal Data, please feel free to [contact us](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) directly. We will respond to your request within 30 days or as appropriate under applicable data protection laws. If we are unable to honor your request or need more time, we will provide you with an explanation.

##### Your choices and selecting your communication preferences

We give you the option to receive a variety of information related to our business, programs, websites, and Solutions. You can manage your communication preferences at any time through the following methods:

* By following the instructions included in each promotional email from us to unsubscribe from that mailing
* By completing and submitting this [form](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) or by contacting us via mail at: Cisco Systems, Inc., Privacy Office, 170 West Tasman Dr., San Jose, CA 95134, USA. Please be sure to include your name, email address, the communication received, method of delivery (such as post, email, phone call, text), and any additional information about the material you no longer wish to receive.
* For short message service (“SMS”) messages, reply “STOP,” “END,” or “QUIT” to the SMS text message you have received

These choices do not apply to service notifications or other required communications that are considered part of certain programs, websites, and Solutions which you may receive periodically unless you cancel or stop use in accordance with its terms and conditions. With your permission, your Personal Data may be shared with third parties (such as Cisco business partners or vendors) so that they may inform you about websites, programs, products, or services that may be of interest to you. To opt out of Cisco sharing with third parties for their marketing purposes, please submit a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/).

By using or engaging with our websites or Solutions, or otherwise providing Personal Data to us, you agree that we may communicate with you regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use. For example, if we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you by posting a notice on our websites, sending an email, or otherwise contacting you.

##### Disclosing your Personal Data

Personal Data may be processed by third parties for the purposes of operating our business; delivering, analyzing, improving, securing, and customizing our websites and Solutions; sending marketing and other communications related to our business; and for other legitimate purposes permitted by applicable law(s); or otherwise with your consent.

Personal Data may be disclosed in the following ways:

* Within Cisco and any of our worldwide subsidiaries for the purposes of data processing, such as marketing, business operations, compliance, security, website or Solution functionality, or storage
* With business partners, service vendors, authorized third-party agents, or contractors to provide a requested website, Solution, service, or transaction. Examples include processing of orders and credit card transactions, hosting websites, hosting seminar registration, assisting with sales-related efforts or pre/post-sales support, and providing customer support.
* With Cisco business partners or vendors, so that they may share information with you about their products or services. To opt out of Cisco sharing with third parties for their marketing purposes, please submit a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/).
* In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or to another company
* In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or to another company
* With law enforcement officials, government authorities, or other third parties as necessary to comply with legal process or meet national security requirements; protect the rights, property, or safety of Cisco, our business partners, you, or others; or as otherwise required by applicable law
* In aggregated, anonymized, and/or de-identified form that cannot reasonably be used to identify you
* If we otherwise notify you and you consent to the sharing

##### Security of your Personal Data

We take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the Personal Data entrusted to us and treat it securely in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Cisco implements physical, technical, and organizational safeguards designed to protect your Personal Data from accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, and unauthorized disclosure or access. We also contractually require that our suppliers protect such information from accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure, or access.

##### Retention and disposal of Personal Data

We will retain your Personal Data as needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. We will retain and use your Personal Data as necessary to comply with our business requirements and legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect our assets, and enforce our rights and agreements.

We will not retain Personal Data in identifiable form when the purpose(s) for which the Personal Data was collected have been achieved and there is no legal or business need to retain such Personal Data. Thereafter, the data will either be destroyed, deleted, anonymized, and/or removed from our systems.

##### Use of cookies and similar technologies

Cisco uses automatic data collection tools, such as cookies, embedded web links, pixels, tags, and web beacons. These tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to us (such as Internet Protocol \[IP\] address, MAC address, clickstream behavior, and telemetry).

These tools help make your visit to our websites and Solutions easier, more efficient, and personalized. We also use the information to improve our websites and Solutions, provide greater service and value, better understand your potential interest in our websites and Solutions, and provide you with more relevant ads and other content.

We partner with third parties to display advertising on our website and to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies to provide you with advertising based on your browsing activities and interests. Where this type of third party advertising is disabled, generic, non-personalized ads will continue to be displayed.

For more information, or if you would like to opt out of interest-based advertising, see [How Cisco Uses Automatic Data Collection Tools](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#automatic-data-collection-tools).

To update your cookie preferences, click the “Cookies” link at the bottom of any page on this website. Additionally, you may be able to use other tools to control cookies and similar technologies. For example, you may have controls in your internet browser to limit how the websites you visit are able to use cookies.

##### Automated decision-making

We process Personal Data using both manual and automated methods of processing. Automated methods are often used to assist our manual methods in accordance with applicable laws. Where an individual’s rights and legitimate interests may be impacted by such automated decision-making, we will provide the impacted individual the opportunity to inquire about the decision or request manual review. Manual review may be conducted by Cisco employees or trusted third-party business partners working on Cisco’s behalf.

##### Linked websites

We may provide links to other third-party websites and services that are outside Cisco’s control and governed by the respective third party’s privacy policy, not by this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy statements posted on the websites you visit and in the applications you use.

##### Forums and chat rooms

If you participate in a discussion forum, local communities, or chat room on a Cisco website, you should be aware that the information you provide there (such as your public profile and comments) will be made broadly available to others and could be used to contact you, to send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes neither Cisco nor you have control over. Also, please recognize that individual forums and chat rooms may have additional rules and conditions. Cisco is not responsible for the Personal Data or any other information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your Personal Data from our blog or community forum, please submit a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/). In some cases, we may not be able to remove all Personal Data and comments. In such cases, we will provide you with a response and explanation.

##### Children’s privacy

Cisco encourages parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities. Cisco does not knowingly collect Personal Data from children without appropriate parental or guardian consent. If you believe that we may have collected Personal Data from someone under the applicable age of consent in your country without proper consent, please let us know using the methods described in the [Questions, comments, and how to contact us](#privacy-contact) section and we will take appropriate measures to investigate and address the issue promptly.

##### International transfer, processing, and storage of Personal Data

As Cisco is a global organization, Personal Data may be transferred to Cisco in the United States of America, to any Cisco subsidiary worldwide, or to third parties and business partners as described above that are located in various jurisdictions around the world. Similarly, Personal Data may be accessed from countries where Cisco or its subsidiaries have operations. Cisco will transfer your Personal Data in accordance with approved transfer mechanisms as well as any applicable local legal requirements.

By using our websites and Solutions or providing any Personal Data to us, where applicable law permits, you acknowledge and accept the transfer, processing, and storage of such information outside of your country of residence where data protection standards may be different.

Cisco safeguards and enables the global transfer of Personal Data in a number of ways:

* ##### APEC Privacy Certification
    
    Cisco’s global privacy program, described in this Privacy Statement, complies with the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Cross-Border Privacy Rules system (CBPRs) and Privacy Recognition for Processors (PRP). The APEC CBPR system and PRP provides a framework for organizations to ensure protection of Personal Data transferred among participating APEC economies. More information about the APEC Privacy Framework, CBPRs, and PRP can be found on the [CBPRs site](http://cbprs.org/). Our certification applies to our business processes across our global operations that process and transfer Personal Data to/from our affiliates around the world. To view our certifications, please see the [APEC CBPR System Directory](http://cbprs.org/compliance-directory/cbpr-system/) and the [APEC PRP Directory](http://cbprs.org/compliance-directory/prp/).
    
    For more information on the scope of our participation, or to [submit a privacy inquiry through BBB National Programs](https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/GlobalPrivacyDivision/gpd-complaints-portal), our Accountability Agent, please click on the official seal below:

* ##### EU Binding Corporate Rules – Controller
    
    Cisco’s global privacy program and policies have been approved by the Dutch, Polish, Spanish, and other relevant European privacy regulators as providing additional safeguards for the protection of privacy, fundamental rights, and freedoms of individuals for transfers of Personal Data protected under European law. Cisco’s Binding Corporate Rules—Controller (BCR-C) provide that international transfers made worldwide by Cisco entities bound by these rules as a controller of European Personal Data benefit from appropriate safeguards.
    
    A copy of our BCR-C can be found in our [Global Privacy Policy](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/trust-center/global-privacy-policy.html). More information about BCRs can be found on the [European Commission site](https://commission.europa.eu/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/binding-corporate-rules-bcr_en).

* ##### EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework, the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework
    
    **EU/U.K. (and Gibraltar)/Swiss – U.S. transfer of Personal Data**
    
    When we transfer Personal Data out of the European Union (“EU”), European Economic Area (“EEA”), the United Kingdom (“U.K.”)(and Gibraltar), and Switzerland to countries that do not benefit from an adequacy decision, we may rely on Standard Contractual Clauses, Binding Corporate Rules—Controller, or other legal transfer mechanisms with appropriate safeguards in place to protect Personal Data. Additionally, Cisco Systems, Inc. and its [U.S. based subsidiaries](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/participant-search/participant-detail?id=a2zt0000000GnJ2AAK&status=Active) (collectively “Cisco-U.S.”) comply with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (EU-U.S. DPF), the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (Swiss-U.S. DPF) for transfers of Personal Data from the EU, EEA, U.K. (and Gibraltar), and Switzerland to the U.S.
    
    **Data Privacy Framework**
    
    Cisco-U.S. has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. DPF Principles with regards to the processing of Personal Data received from the EU and EEA in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and from the U.K. (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF. Cisco-U.S. has also certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles with regards to the processing of Personal Data received from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Online Privacy Statement and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the DPF Principles shall govern. For more information about the DPF program, and to view our certification, please visit the [DPF Website.](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/)
    
    Pursuant to the DPF Principles, Cisco-U.S. commits to the following:
    
    * Cisco-U.S. is responsible for the processing of Personal Data it receives under the DPF, and subsequently may transfer it to third parties acting as agents on its behalf. Cisco-U.S. complies with the DPF Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Data from the EU, EEA, U.K. (and Gibraltar), and Switzerland (for examples of such transfers, see [Disclosing your Personal Data](#spi) ), including the onward transfer liability provisions. In certain situations, Cisco-U.S. may be required to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Further, Cisco-U.S. is committed to protecting Personal Data received from EU and EEA member countries, Switzerland, and the U.K. (and Gibraltar) (see [Collection and use of your Personal Data](#personal-information) for examples of the Personal Data Cisco processes when you use our websites and Solutions and interact with us) in accordance with the DPF’s applicable Principles and to help ensure Personal Data collected from individuals is accessible to them as part of their individual rights when Cisco is the Controller of the Personal Data (see [Your privacy rights](#privacy-rights)). Furthermore, Cisco acknowledges the right of EU, EEA, U.K. (and Gibraltar), and Swiss individuals to request access to their data while it is in the U.S. and to correct, amend, and supplement inaccurate or incomplete data. Said individuals also have the right to request erasure of personal information that has been handled in violation of the DPF Principles. Subject individuals interested in accessing their data should see [Disclosing your Personal Data](#spi) for information on how to contact us, or submit a Privacy Request online.
    * In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, Cisco-U.S. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Data transferred to the U.S. pursuant to the DPF Principles. EU, EEA, U.K. (and Gibraltar), and Swiss individuals with DPF inquiries or complaints, or any questions or concerns regarding Cisco-U.S. processing or international transfer of their Personal Data should first contact Cisco-U.S. by submitting a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) online.
    * Cisco-U.S. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the DPF Principles to a U.S.-based independent third-party dispute resolution mechanism, DPF Services, operated by BBB National Programs. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/dpf-consumers/ProcessForConsumers](https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/dpf-consumers/ProcessForConsumers) for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.
    * If your DPF complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/G-Arbitration-Procedures-dpf?tabset-35584=2](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/G-Arbitration-Procedures-dpf?tabset-35584=2).
    * Cisco-U.S. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

##### Complaint resolution

Cisco commits to resolve complaints and concerns about your privacy and our collection and use of your Personal Data. If you have concerns or complaints about your privacy and our collection and use of your Personal Data, please contact us via the [Privacy Request Form](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/).

For complaints or concerns about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Data transferred to the U.S. pursuant to the DPF Principles, please see [Data Privacy Framework.](#data)

Alternatively, you can contact the data protection supervisory authority in your jurisdiction for assistance. (Note, Cisco’s main establishment in the EU is in the Netherlands. As such, our EU lead authority is the [Dutch Autoritiet Persoonsgegevens](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en).)

##### Your California privacy rights

###### California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) / California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA)

For business purposes in the last 12 months, Cisco may have collected, used, and shared Personal Data about you as described in this Privacy Statement. Each category of data that may be used by Cisco or shared with third parties is categorically outlined in this Privacy Statement.

California consumers have a right to: (1) request access, correction, and deletion of their Personal Data, (2) opt out of the sale or sharing of their Personal Data, and (3) not be discriminated against for exercising one of their California privacy rights.

All individuals have the right to request access to and deletion of the information Cisco holds about them either online via the Cisco [Privacy Request Form](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) or by mail to Cisco Systems, Inc., Privacy Office, 170 West Tasman Dr., San Jose, CA 95134, USA.

In addition, California residents may also submit a request by calling direct 408-906-2726 or toll free 833-774-2726 (833-PRI-CSCO).

Cisco does not sell the Personal Data of California consumers.

Cisco does not discriminate against individuals for exercising their privacy rights.

View the [Cisco CCPA Metrics Report](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/legal/2020-ccpa-metrics-report.html).

###### California Shine the Light

Residents of the State of California, under California Civil Code § 1798.83, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Data during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt out or opt in choice for use of your Personal Data by third parties (such as advertisers) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

Cisco has a comprehensive Privacy Statement and provides you with details on how you may either opt-out or opt-in to the use of your Personal Data by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain nor disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Data for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

##### Updates to this Cisco Privacy Statement

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. If we modify our Privacy Statement, we will post the revised version here with an updated revision date. If we make material changes to our Privacy Statement, we may also notify you by other means, such as by posting a notice on our websites or sending you a notification. By continuing to use our website after such revisions are in effect, you accept and agree to the revisions and to abide by them.

##### The Cisco Privacy Statement was revised and effective as of September 26, 2023.

Click [here](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/legal/privacy-full/previous-2022.html) for the previous version of the Privacy Statement.

##### Questions, comments, and how to contact us

We value your opinion. Should you have questions or comments related to this Privacy Statement, please submit a [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) or send mail to:

**Chief Privacy Officer**  
Cisco Systems, Inc.  
170 West Tasman Dr.  
San Jose, CA 95134 USA

**Americas Privacy Officer**  
Cisco Systems, Inc.  
170 West Tasman Dr.  
San Jose, CA 95134 USA

**Europe, Middle East, and Africa (EMEA) Privacy Officer**  
Cisco Systems International BV  
Haarlerbergweg 13-19,  
1101 CH Amsterdam-Zuidoost, Netherlands

**Asia Pacific, Japan, and China (APJC) Privacy Officer**  
Cisco Systems (USA) Pte Ltd  
80 Pasir Panjang Road  
Level 25, Maple Tree Business City 2  
Singapore 117372

Online Privacy Statement Summary
--------------------------------

* * *

The [Cisco Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy) and this summary apply to Cisco websites and products and services (“Solutions”) that link to or reference the Online Privacy Statement and describes how we handle Personal Data and the choices available to you regarding collection, use, access, and how to update and correct your Personal Data.

* Cisco respects and is committed to protecting Personal Data. Our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy) reflects current global principles and standards on handling Personal Data – transparency, fairness, and accountability.
* Our Privacy Policies and practices are designed to comply with applicable laws around the world and to earn and maintain your trust in Cisco.

Below are some of the highlights of our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy). Note, additional information on our Personal Data practices with respect to Cisco Solutions may be provided in Solution-specific [privacy data sheets and maps](https://trustportal.cisco.com/c/r/ctp/trust-portal.html?doctype=Privacy%20Data%20Map%7CPrivacy%20Data%20Sheet), offer descriptions, or other notices provided prior to or at the time of data collection.

##### Collection and use of Personal Data

* We collect Personal Data for a variety of reasons, which may include processing your order, providing our various websites and other Solutions, providing you with a newsletter subscription, sending business and marketing communications, personalizing your experience, and processing job applications.
* We will use your Personal Data for the purposes stated in our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy) or such other privacy notices that we may make available (e.g., our Privacy Data Sheets, site or event-specific privacy notices, etc.).
* We may lawfully combine the information we collect from you with information obtained from other sources to help us improve its overall accuracy and completeness and to help us improve and better tailor our interactions and performance with you.
* We may also collect information relating to your use of our websites and web-based Solutions through the use of various technologies, including cookies.

##### Notice and your choices of data use

* We will use your Personal Data for the purpose for which it was collected and will not use it for a different purpose without first asking for your permission or having a legal basis for the use.
* We will ask your permission before we share your Personal Data with third parties for any purpose other than the reason you provided it or as otherwise stated in our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy).
* For more information on your choices about how Cisco may process your Personal Data or regarding our use of cookies or other web technologies, see our full [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy).

##### Your privacy rights

* Various data protection laws around the world provide individuals with certain rights regarding their Personal Data. This may include the right to access, correct, delete, object to, or limit the processing of your Personal Data, or to submit a complaint to your local data protection authority. To learn more about your privacy rights, see our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy).
* To submit a request to exercise your privacy rights or to update your communication preferences, please use the [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) form.

##### Data security

* We are committed to protecting your Personal Data against unauthorized use or disclosure.

##### International data transfers

* As a global organization, Cisco Systems, Inc. and other Cisco Group Companies, as well as their respective business partners and suppliers, operate in countries located around the world. Cisco will transfer your Personal Data in accordance with approved transfer mechanisms as well as any applicable local legal requirements.
* Regardless of where your Personal Data is processed, we implement appropriate safeguards to protect your Personal Data. For example, we enter into data protection agreements with our suppliers requiring them to adhere to a minimum standard for protecting your Personal Data. We have also implemented the following safeguards:
    * Cisco is certified under the APEC [Cross Border Privacy Rules system](http://cbprs.org/compliance-directory/cbpr-system/)and [Privacy Recognition for Processors](http://cbprs.org/compliance-directory/prp/) regarding personal data handling and transfers to/from the APEC member economies. For more information on the scope of our participation, or to [submit a privacy inquiry through BBB National Programs](https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/GlobalPrivacyDivision/gpd-complaints-portal), our Accountability Agent, please click on the official seal below:

    * Cisco’s [Binding Corporate Rules – Controller (BCR-C)](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/trust-center/global-privacy-policy.html) provide that transfers made worldwide by Cisco entities bound by these rules as a controller of European Personal Data benefit from appropriate safeguards.
    * Cisco is also certified and adheres to the [EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (EU-U.S. DPF), the U.K. Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (Swiss-U.S. DPF)](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and processing of Personal Data from the EU, EEA, the U.K. (and Gibraltar), and Switzerland.
    * Cisco may also use the EU Standard Contractual Clauses (and/or their U.K. and Switzerland counterparts) to provide additional safeguards for Personal Data collected from the EU and EEA, the U.K., and Switzerland.

##### Questions, comments, or concerns

* Should you have questions, comments or concerns related to this Privacy Statement or the treatment of your Personal Data, please use the [Privacy Request](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) form.
* If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please [contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider](https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/bbb-eu-privacy-shield/privacy-shield-complaints) (free of charge).

##### More information

* To find out more about our privacy practices, see the full version of our [Online Privacy Statement](https://meraki.cisco.com/meraki-support/policies/#privacy-policy) or such other privacy notices that we may make available (e.g., our Privacy Data Sheets, site-specific privacy notices, etc.).

_Last updated: September 26, 2023_

Automatic Data Collection Tools (Cookies, etc.)
-----------------------------------------------

* * *

##### Cisco use of cookies and other tracking technologies

Our services (including our websites, web-based products and services, mobile apps, e-mail, and marketing/advertising communications, together the “services”) use cookies and other similar device identification technologies (collectively “cookies”) to provide our services, to understand how they are used, and for analytics, personalization, customization and marketing/advertising purposes. You can read more about the types of cookies we (Cisco and our third-party service providers) use, why we use them, and how you can exercise your cookies choices below.

Our services may also include “widgets,” which are interactive mini programs that run on our sites to provide specific services from other companies (such as displaying the news, opinions, music, and more). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the widget. Cookies may also be set by the widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by these widgets is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

##### What are cookies?

We use the term “cookie” to refer to all technologies which store and access information on the device that you use to access our services, such as your computer, tablet, or mobile phone. For example, we use HTTP cookies (web/browser cookies), which are small data files (typically made up of numbers and letters) that are downloaded when you access our services and allow us to recognize your device. Click here for more information on cookies.

Cookies can be necessary and useful in a number of ways. For example, cookies enable websites to recognize your device and are often used to help the website function properly and to provide information to the owner(s) of the site. Cookies are necessary to recognize or “remember” anything about visitors, such as:

1. Whether a visitor is logged in
2. User-selected preferences
3. Items put in a user’s shopping cart

There are different types of cookies, including:

* Cookies served (i.e., set, shared, provided, offered) directly by Cisco (“first party cookies”) and cookies served on our behalf, for example by advertising and data analytics service providers (“third party cookies”)
* Cookies that only last as long as your browser is open are referred to as “session cookies.” Session cookies are deleted automatically when you close your browser.
* Other cookies are “persistent cookies” and remain after your browser is closed, until cleared. For example, they store your device identifier and recognize your device when you open and use your browser.

#### Which cookies do we use, and why do we use them?

The following table sets out the different types of cookies that our services use, why they are served them, and who serves them.

**Type of cookie**

**Why we use these cookies**

**Who serves them**

Essential Authentication Cookies

These cookies (including local storage and similar technologies) tell us when you are logged in, so we can show you the appropriate experience and features such as your account information, trip history, and to edit your account settings.

Cisco

Security and site integrity cookies

We use these cookies to support or enable security features to help keep Cisco safe and secure. For example, they enable us to remember when you are logged into a secure area of the services and help protect your account from being accessed by anyone other than you.

* OneTrust Cookie Consent
* TrustArc Privacy Compliance

Advertising

Things like cookies and pixels are used to understand and deliver ads, make them more relevant, and track the efficacy of mobile application advertising campaigns.  
For example, we may read a cookie so we can serve you ads that may be interesting (including personalized or customized) on other websites. We also use this information to retarget users with relevant advertising. Similarly, our partners may use a cookie, attribution service, or other similar technology to determine whether we have served an ad and how it performed or provide us with information about how you interact with them. This may involve storing cookies on your local device.

* Adform
* Amazon Advertising
* AppNexus
* Baidu
* Bing Ad
* Facebook Conversion
* Facebook Events
* Floodlight Counter
* Google Ads Conversion Tracking
* Google Ads Remarketing
* Google Analytics
* Google Global Site
* Google Universal Analytics
* Index Exchange
* iPinYou
* LinkedIn
* LinkedIn Insights
* Nielsen DMP
* OpenX
* Oracle Bluekai
* PubMatic
* Rubicon
* Samsung Ads
* Sizmek
* StackAdapt
* TradeDesk
* Triplelift
* Twitter Analytics Conversion
* Twitter Conversion Tracker
* Yahoo Analytics

Analytics Localization

These help Cisco provide a localized experience. For example, we may store information in a cookie that is placed on your browser or device so you see the site in your preferred language.

Cisco

Site features and Services

These provide functionality that help us deliver products and services. For example, cookies help you log in by pre-filling fields. We may also use cookies and similar technologies to help us provide you and others with social plugins and other customized content and experiences.

* Adobe Visitor ID
* Brightcove
* Cisco Cocoa Chat
* Marketo
* OpinionLab Pixel
* PriceSpider
* Qualtrics
* SalesForce Chat

Analytics and research

These are used to understand, improve, and research products and services, including when you access the Cisco website and related websites and apps from a computer or mobile device. For example, we may use cookies to understand how you are using site features, and segmenting audiences for feature testing. We and our partners may use these technologies and the information we receive to improve and understand how you use websites, apps, products, services, and ads. We may share information about this analysis with our partners.

* 6sense
* Adobe Analytics
* Adobe Audience Manager
* Adobe Target
* Adobe Visitor ID
* AppDynamics
* Bidswitch
* Bing Tracking
* Bizible
* Cision Pixel
* Clicktale/Content Square
* Cloudfront Loader
* comScore Mobile Metrix
* comScore Video Metrix
* DrawBridge
* Google Analytics 4
* Google Tag Manager
* IBM Watson Marketing
* Marketo
* NewsCred Analytics
* Nielsen Visual IQ
* Oracle Eloqua
* SalesForce Email studio
* Sprinklr
* Tealium
* Zift Analytics

#### How can you exercise your cookies choices?

You have the right to choose not to accept certain cookies. However, even optional cookies are an important part of how our services work, so you should be aware that if you choose to refuse or remove certain cookies, this could affect the usability and functionality of our services.

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. To do so, follow the instructions provided in your browser. Instructions are generally located within the “Help,” “Tools,” or “Edit” menus.

Some third parties also provide the ability to refuse advertising cookies directly by clicking on an opt-out link or you can opt-out proactively. How to opt out of interest-based advertising:

* If you are located [in the European Union](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)
* If you are located [in Canada](https://youradchoices.ca/)
* If you are located [in all other parts of the world](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)

Removing or rejecting browser cookies does not necessarily affect third-party flash cookies used in connection with our services. [Get more information](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) on how to delete or disable flash cookies.

You can also change your preferences in relation to how this website uses cookies.

#### For more information

For further information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit AllAboutCookies.org and Your Online Choices (for European Union residents).

For further information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit [AllAboutCookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [Your Online Choices](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (for European Union residents).

#### “Do not track” function

Some web browsers may give you the ability to enable a “do not track” feature that sends signals to the services you visit, indicating that you do not want your online activities tracked. This is different than blocking or deleting cookies as browsers with a “do not track” feature enabled may still accept cookies. There is currently no industry standard for how companies should respond to “do not track” signals, although one may develop in the future. Cisco does not respond to “do not track” signals currently. If Cisco does so in the future, we will describe how in this privacy statement. Learn more information about [“do not track.”](https://allaboutdnt.com/)

#### Contact us

If you have any questions about our use of cookies, please click [here](https://privacyrequest.cisco.com/) to contact us.

Last updated: October 31, 2022.

Website Terms of Use
--------------------

* * *

Last Updated: March 3, 2022

Why, hello there! Welcome to [https://meraki.cisco.com](https://meraki.cisco.com/)! This site is operated by Cisco Meraki (hereinafter “**Meraki**”, **“we”, “us”** or “**our**”). The following terms and conditions (“**Terms of Use**”) govern your use of this website as well as any other websites that Meraki may control (collectively, the “**Site**”). Your use of the Site is subject to our [**Privacy Policy**](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/legal/privacy-full.html), including our [**Cookie Policy**](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/legal/privacy-full.html#cookies), which is incorporated into these Terms of Use by reference. BY USING THE SITE IN ANY WAY, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTOOD AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THESE TERMS OF USE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE, DO NOT USE THE SITE.

**Changes to the Terms of Use, Site and Site Content**

All materials and information on the Site, including but not limited to Cisco Meraki products and services, prices, text, files, images, logos, sounds and videos (collectively, “**Site Content**”), is owned or licensed by or to Meraki. Meraki reserves the right, in its sole discretion and without any liability, to make changes to these Terms of Use, the Site and any Site Content, wholly or partly, at any time without prior notice. The changes will be effective at the time of posting and your continued use of the Site will be deemed as acceptance of the changes. If you disagree with any change, your sole remedy is to cease using the Site. Meraki makes no commitment to update the Site regularly and therefore some Site Content may be out of date. If you require assistance, please contact your local sales representative for complete information on products and services availability in your country.

**License to Use Site and Software**

Nothing in these Terms of Use confers, by implication, estoppel, or otherwise, any license or intellectual property rights of Meraki, its affiliates and subsidiaries, or of any third party. All rights not expressly licensed are reserved by Meraki. Subject to these Terms of Use, Meraki grants you a limited, revocable, non-sublicensable license to access and use the Site solely for the purpose of purchasing, researching or conducting other relevant activities related to Meraki’s products and services. No other use of the Site is authorized without our prior written consent.

Any software that is made available to download from the Site (“**Software**“) is pursuant to a separate software license agreement that accompanies the Software, which shall be the governing agreement between Meraki and you with respect to that Software. You agree to comply with the terms and conditions found in such software license agreement prior to using the Software.

**Account Registration**

You may be required to register for an account to gain access or to use certain Meraki services. You agree to provide accurate, current and complete information while registering for any such account. You understand that the account may not be used by any other person or entity, and you shall assume full responsibility for all activities that happens through your account. You are responsible for keeping your password(s) confidential and must immediately notify Meraki should there be a breach in any way. You may be liable for losses suffered by Meraki or any other Site user as a result of your failure to keep your password confidential. Meraki is not liable to you or to any third party for any loss or damage resulting from any unauthorized access of your account. It is your responsibility to obtain and maintain all equipment and payments of related charges (i.e. internet fees) to access the Site.

**Privacy Policy**

Please read our [**Privacy Policy**](https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/legal/privacy-full.html) carefully for information relating to our collection, use, storage and disclosure of your personal information that we may collect through the Site. Although Meraki has taken reasonable and appropriate steps to protect your personal information and have implemented strong security and technical safeguards, we do not guarantee that Internet transmissions will always be completely private or secure.

**User Content and Feedback**

We do not have ownership rights on any text, files, images, videos, or other materials that you may upload or otherwise provide to our Site (collectively, “**User Content**“). Meraki may, in its sole discretion, decline or delete any User Content that it reasonably believes violates these Terms of Use or any applicable law. Under no circumstances will Meraki be liable for any loss or damage incurred in connection with any User Content. You agree that you are responsible for any feedback that you provide to us, and any such feedback shall be deemed non-proprietary and non-confidential. Meraki may use your feedback in any way without limitation, including for future modifications to the Site and our Site Content.

**Usage Restrictions**

You must comply with all applicable laws when using the Site. Except as may be expressly permitted by applicable law or expressly permitted by us in writing, you will not, and will not permit anyone else to: (a) store, copy, modify, distribute, or resell any Site Content or compile or collect any Site Content as part of a database or other work; (b) use any automated tool (e.g., robots, spiders) to use the Site or store, copy, modify, distribute, or resell any Site Content; (c) rent, lease, or sublicense your access to the Site; (d) use the Site and Site Content for any purpose except as agreed to in these Terms of Use or upload any User Content in any manner that may infringe any intellectual property right, proprietary right, or property right of us or any third parties; (e) circumvent or disable any digital rights management, usage rules, or other security features of the Site; (f) reproduce, modify, translate, enhance, decompile, disassemble, reverse engineer, or create derivative works of the Site or Site Content; (g) use the Site in a manner that threatens the integrity, performance, or availability of the Site; or (h) remove, alter, or obscure any proprietary notices on any portion of the Site or Site Content.

**Trademarks**

We, or our affiliates or licensors, or applicable third parties, retain all rights and title to any registered or unregistered trademarks, logos or service marks displayed on the Site (“**Marks**”). The Marks are protected by applicable intellectual property laws and may be used under limited circumstances in strict accordance with our Trademark Guidelines available [here](https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en_us/about/ac50/ac47/downloads/logo/trademark.pdf). Otherwise, you are not permitted to use these Marks without the prior written consent of Meraki or any third party that may own the Mark.

**Disclosure; Forward-Looking Statements**

Some of the information on this Site may contain projections or other forward-looking statements regarding future events or future financial performance of Meraki and/or Cisco. We wish to caution you that these statements are only predictions and that actual events or results may differ materially. We refer you to the documents Cisco files from time to time with the Securities and Exchange Commission, specifically, Cisco’s most recent Form 10-K, Form 10-Q, and Form 10-Q/A. These documents contain and identify important factors that could cause the actual results to differ materially from those contained in our projections or forward-looking statements, including, among others, potential fluctuations in quarterly results, dependence on new product development; rapid technological and market change, acquisition strategy, manufacturing risks, risks associated with Internet infrastructure, volatility of stock price, financial risk management, and future growth subject to risks.

**Promotions**

If you take part in any promotion that we may offer on the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions that govern that promotion. You also agree to accept any decision that Meraki and our designees make which are discretionary and final in all matters relating to any promotion.

**Links to External Sites**

The Site may provide links to third party products, services, and websites (“**External Sites**”) solely for your convenience and shall not be considered as endorsements by us. If you navigate away from this Site by following a link, you do so at your sole risk and understand that these Terms of Use, including the Privacy Policy, will no longer govern your usage. We have no control over any External Sites and are not responsible, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss suffered by you in connection with any content, products or services available through External Sites.

**Disclaimer of Warranties**

UNLESS REQUIRED BY LAW, MERAKI AND ITS AFFILIATES, AND THEIR RESPECTIVE OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUPPLIERS AND LICENSORS (COLLECTIVELY, “**MERAKI PARTIES**”) EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT, AND ANY WARRANTIES ARISING FROM A COURSE OF DEALING, USAGE, OR TRADE PRACTICE. YOUR USE OF THE SITE, THE SITE CONTENT, INCLUDING ANY SUBMISSION BY YOU OR ANYONE USING YOUR ACCOUNT, AND RESULTS YOU RECEIVE FROM THE SITE, IS AT YOUR SOLE DISCRETION AND RISK. THE SITE AND SITE CONTENT ARE PROVIDED ON AN “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE” BASIS.  THE MERAKI PARTIES DO NOT GUARANTEE THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, OR USEFULNESS OF THE SITE OR SITE CONTENT, OR THAT THE SITE WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, ERROR-FREE, VIRUS-FREE, SECURE, TIMELY OR THAT ANY DEFECT WILL BE CORRECTED. YOU WILL BE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF ANY MATERIAL THROUGH THE SITE. NO ADVICE OR INFORMATION, WHETHER ORAL OR WRITTEN, OBTAINED BY YOU FROM THIS SITE OR FROM ANY MERAKI PARTY WILL CREATE ANY WARRANTY NOT EXPRESSLY AGREED IN WRITING. YOUR SOLE REMEDY FOR ANY DISSATISFACTION WITH THE SITE OR ANY SITE CONTENT IS TO CEASE USING THE SITE OR THE SITE CONTENT.

**Limitation of Liability**

IN NO EVENT SHALL ANY MERAKI PARTY BE LIABLE TO YOU OR TO ANY THIRD PARTY FOR ANY INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, CONSEQUENTIAL, OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF PROFITS OR REVENUES, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, GOODWILL, USE, DATA OR OTHER INTANGIBLE LOSSES ARISING FROM YOUR USE AND ACCESS OF THE SITE AND SITE CONTENT, OR DAMAGES RELATED TO YOUR RELIANCE ON ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THE WEBSITE. THIS SECTION APPLIES WHETHER DAMAGES ARE BASED ON WARRANTY, CONTRACT, TORT, STATUTE, OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY AND EVEN IF ANY MERAKI PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF THESE DAMAGES.

THE TOTAL CUMULATIVE LIABILITY OF THE MERAKI PARTIES FOR ALL CLAIMS TO YOU OR TO ANY THIRD PARTY UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCE WILL NOT EXCEED $50 USD. BECAUSE SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, THE ABOVE LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. IN SUCH STATES, THE LIABILITY OF THE MERAKI PARTIES WILL BE LIMITED TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.

**Indemnity**

You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold Meraki Parties harmless from and against any and all claims, costs, damages, expenses, liabilities or fees (including reasonable attorney fees) arising out of or in any way connected to your violation of these Terms of Use and any rights of Meraki or a third party through your use of the Site or Site Content. Meraki shall have exclusive control over the defense of any matter which is subject to indemnification under this section, and you agree to fully cooperate with Meraki’s reasonable requests in such cases.

**Termination**

Meraki reserves the right to terminate, suspend or restrict your current and future use of the Site, in whole or in part, at any time for any reason without notice and liability. You may discontinue your access to and use of this Site at any time. If you breach any of these Terms of Use or any applicable law, we will automatically terminate your access. We reserve the right to investigate and take appropriate action against anyone who, in Meraki’s sole discretion, is suspected of violating any applicable law or violating Meraki’s or any third party’s rights (either intentionally or unintentionally) under these Terms of Use. Meraki’s rights hereunder will survive termination of your use of the Site and shall continue in full force and effect.

**Governing Law**

These Terms of Use will be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of California without regard to principles of conflicts of law. You submit to the jurisdiction of the federal or state courts of or located in Santa Clara County, California, with respect to any action or proceeding arising out of or in any way related to these Terms of Use. You hereby waive any venue or other objection which you may have to any such action or proceeding being brought in the federal or state courts of in Santa Clara County, California, U.S.A.

**Export Compliance**

You agree to comply with all export and re-export laws and regulations of United States and any foreign jurisdictions in connection with your use of the Site. By downloading any Site Content, you expressly warrant that you are not in a country where such export is prohibited or are an entity or person to whom such export is prohibited.

**Miscellaneous**

No failure or delay by us in exercising any right under these Terms of Use will constitute a waiver of that right. If any portion of these Terms of Use is held unenforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction, then such portion will be limited or eliminated to the extent necessary, and the rest of the terms will remain in full force and effect. The headings used in these Terms of Use are for convenience only and do not affect the meaning of these Terms of Use. These Terms of Use shall be interpreted as to its fair meaning and not strictly for or against any party. Any rights and licenses granted hereunder may not be transferred or assigned by you but may be automatically assigned by Meraki without restriction. To the extent that anything in or associated with the Site is inconsistent with these Terms of Use, the latter shall take precedence.

**Contacting Meraki**

If you have any questions or concerns about these Terms of Use or the Site, including but not limited to notices of intellectual property infringement, please send us a thorough description by email to legal@meraki.com, or write to us at:

Cisco Meraki

500 Terry A Francois  
San Francisco, CA 94158  
United States of America

Shipping Policy
---------------

* * *

##### Orders

All orders will generally be processed the same day and shipped within 2 business days. Once the order is processed, the customer will receive a confirmation email. Delays may occur in case of missing information, special shipping requests, and if import/export related verification is required.

##### Order Number

A single Cisco CCW Sales Order can be transmitted to Meraki as multiple Meraki orders due to the below scenarios and will ship separately. Shipping charges will be billed per Meraki order, not per the SO as a whole.

* Duplicate PID
* Different License duration
* Different license addition for MX only (ENT/SEC)
* Different ship ID address
* Different end user ID
* Different request ship date
* Different freight account #
* Different ship method

##### P.O. Boxes

For most addresses, PO Boxes are not acceptable delivery addresses. If your shipping address must include a PO Box, Cisco Meraki cannot guarantee delivery.

##### Sales Tax and VAT

In accordance with applicable law, Cisco Meraki collects sales tax or VAT in regions where Cisco Meraki has a presence. Sales tax or VAT will be applied to the total amount of the order and is based on the shipment’s destination and local sales tax or VAT rates.

##### Special Delivery Requirements

In case you require any special service for your delivery such as a lift gate or indoor delivery service, or have special export/import requirements, please make sure to let your seller know to include this information on the PO or open a case on the [Cisco Customer Service Portal](http://customerservice.cloudapps.cisco.com/) prior order submission to allow sufficient time for the Cisco-Meraki shipping team to review and advise.

##### International Certifications

Cisco Meraki has products certified in countries all over the world. If you have specific questions regarding Cisco Meraki certifications, please contact your sales representative.

##### Canceling or Modifying an Order

Orders can be modified or canceled before they have entered the shipping process. Once the shipment is in transit the shipping address can no longer be modified. Please take special care when processing the order to ensure the shipping address is correct and able to accept the delivery. However, if you do require adjustments prior to the shipment, please contact your seller/reseller/distributor or open an urgent case in the [Cisco Customer Service Portal](http://customerservice.cloudapps.cisco.com/) as soon as possible. You may be responsible for any applicable adjustment, handling and/or shipping fees if applicable.

#### Shipping and Delivery

##### Shipping Confirmation

Once your order has been shipped, a shipping notification email will be sent to the email listed in your Purchase Order, containing the tracking number of the shipment and the License Key. In case you ordered the license separately from the hardware product, the License Key will be sent on a separate email.

##### Shipping Methods

Opt In (Cisco-routed) program allows the customer to rely on Cisco’s preferred carrier network, typically gives full end to end tracking visibility for parcel shipments, most freight shipments, and eliminates the need for partner/customer carrier information to be provided. However, the Cisco-routed program does not place liability for lost/damaged shipments wholly on Cisco Meraki. To determine when risk/liability is transferred, refer to the Incoterms. Once ownership of the goods has changed from Cisco Meraki per the Incoterms, goods should not be sent back to Cisco without first obtaining a [Return Material Authorization](https://meraki.cisco.com/support/policies#return-policy-and-requesting-a-rma) (RMA) from Cisco.

Opt Out (self-routed) shipping preference allows the partner or customer to select their own carrier. Cisco Meraki has the ability to ship with most carriers, and the shipping cost will be the responsibility of the bill to party. If there are any concerns with the carrier selected, Cisco Meraki will contact the partner or customer.

##### Incoterms, Duties & Taxes

Cisco Meraki will send shipments with a variety of Incoterms depending on the customer agreement. Incoterms determine and differentiate between the seller’s and the buyer’s responsibility. In the majority of cases, the “bill to” party on the order will be the importer of record and will be responsible for all duties & taxes, VAT, brokerage or other fees. In some cases, third party billing for duty & tax is not available in the destination country and the receiver/”ship to” will be responsible for these fees.

##### Loss/Damage

In the unlikely scenario that you receive your delivery damaged or missing cartons, please accept the shipment and notate as such with the carrier upon delivery. Upon receiving the shipment, take photos to provide supporting information when filing a RMA claim with [Cisco Customer Service](http://customerservice.cloudapps.cisco.com/) to assist in the investigation.

#### Country Specific Information and Transit Times

Each country can have variations in transit time, available ship services and special requirements. Below are the most frequent destinations and estimated delivery times. If there are any further questions, please contact your seller, or open a case on the [Cisco Customer Service Portal.](http://customerservice.cloudapps.cisco.com/)

##### United States

Cisco Meraki will generally ship using Fedex or UPS for parcel, LTL (less than truckload) or FTL (full truckload.) The order will be shipped on Cisco Meraki’s account and billed to the customer if opt in.  
  
NOTE: _Above map is for Opt In parcel shipments with a standard service level. Business Days are Monday through Friday, excluding holidays observed by FedEx and UPS. Expedited shipments within the US using an expedited method will generally arrive in 1-3 business days._

##### Europe

Cisco Meraki will generally ship using Fedex or UPS for parcel, LTL (less than truckload) or FTL (full truckload.) The order will be shipped on Cisco Meraki’s account and billed to the customer if opt in. UPS or FedEx shipment to countries within the EU using a paperless process when this option is offered by the courier and applicable for the territory. The commercial invoice is therefore electronic and will not be included in the shipment.  
  
NOTE: _Above map is for Opt In parcel shipments with a standard service level. Business Days are Monday through Friday, excluding holidays observed by carriers._

##### Mainland China

Cisco Meraki will ship via Jiuli if the product is shipped on Cisco Meraki’s account. The most common methods used are SF Express for Airfreight service and Jiuli for Ground service.

To ensure shipment is delivered to the correct End Customer. Jiuli requires the end customer’s signature and company seal upon delivery. If the company seal is unavailable, the person who signs the POD needs to provide identification.

NOTE: _Above map is for Opt In parcel shipments with a standard service level. Business Days are Monday through Friday, excluding holidays observed by Jiuli. The delivery times suggested here indicate delivery to the capital cities of each province. For non-capital cities, add 1-2 days for each extra city-tier._

##### Japan

Cisco Meraki will ship using Seino Transportation. In case, ship-to address is in an unserviced area by Seino, Cisco Meraki will ship using Yamato transport. To track delivery status, go to [Seino](http://track.seino.co.jp/) or [Yamato](http://track.kuronekoyamato.co.jp/english/tracking) and enter the tracking number from ship notification for the latest update. If total order quantity to one ship to address exceeds 2 pallets, the order is delivered with a chartered truck. Default service of chartered truck is pallet delivery.  
  
NOTE: _Above map is for Opt In parcel shipments with a standard service level. Business Days are Monday through Friday, excluding holidays observed by Seino._

##### Other International Locations

International shipments not going to North America or Europe will generally arrive in 2-5 days. If an opt-in shipping method has been chosen, Cisco-Meraki will ship the orders with the best courier option for the region, typically with UPS. UPS offers different international shipping options depending on the territory: UPS Worldwide Expedited: 2-5 days transit time.

##### Canada

Cisco Meraki will ship to Canada with the best available courier service. Any shipment to Canada will ship via FedEx and use the paperless process. The commercial invoice is therefore electronic and will not be included in the shipment.

Ground service to Canada will generally arrive in 2-7 business days. The further east a shipment has to travel, the longer the transit time. Expedited shipments to Canada using an expedited method will usually lead to decreased transit time depending on the transit times each courier can offer.

##### Mexico

Cisco Meraki will ship any UPS or FedEx parcel shipment, and Expeditors for freight to Mexico using a paperless process. The commercial invoice is therefore electronic and will not be included in the shipment.

Expedited shipments to Mexico will generally arrive in 2-5 business days. Any delays with customs could impact stated delivery lead times.

Australia and New Zealand  
Shipments to Australia and New Zealand will ship from our US distribution centers and will arrive into the country based on the carrier transit capacity, international shipping carriers are different, depending on the receiving country.

Australia: Cisco Meraki will ship via DHL shipments using a paperless process. The commercial invoice is therefore electronic and will not be included in the shipment.

In case of any further questions about shipping, please contact your reseller/distributor, or open a case on the [Cisco Customer Service Portal](http://customerservice.cloudapps.cisco.com/).

End Customer Agreement
----------------------

* * *

##### Last Updated: November 17 , 2020

Use of the Cisco Meraki products is governed by the Meraki Offer Description, published at [https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en\_us/about/doing\_business/legal/OfferDescriptions/meraki.pdf](https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en_us/about/doing_business/legal/OfferDescriptions/meraki.pdf)

Cisco Meraki provides certain translated versions of the Meraki Offer Description at the links below. Please note that these translations are provided for reference purposes only.

To view the Cisco Meraki Offer Description in Japanese, please click [here.](https://meraki.cisco.com/lib/pdf/eol/meraki_offer_description_ja.pdf)

To view the Cisco Meraki Offer Description in Chinese, please click [here.](https://meraki.cisco.com/lib/pdf/eol/meraki_offer_description_cn.pdf)

To view the Cisco Meraki Offer Description in French (Canada), please click [here.](https://meraki.cisco.com/lib/pdf/eol/meraki_offer_description_fr-ca.pdf)

Open Source/Licenses
--------------------

* * *

This page contains versions of the RedBoot bootloader, Linux kernel and OpenWRT distribution modified to run on the Meraki hardware, along with associated licenses. Please note that custom firmware images are not supported by Meraki and may put your device in a non-working state. Devices with custom firmware images are not covered under the limited warranty.

Enjoy!

Third Party Licenses
--------------------

* * *

The following products are subject to the VRT Certified Rules License Agreement:

* MX64
* MX64W
* MX65
* MX65W
* MX84
* MX100
* MX400
* MX600

**View the latest version of the [VRT Certified Rules License Agreement](https://www.snort.org/vrt_license)**.

Systems Manager Free 100 Terms and Conditions
---------------------------------------------

* * *

**Last Updated: April 2017**

**Note:** Sign-ups for the Meraki SM free 100 program have been discontinued and replaced with instant free trials as of the end of January 2017. For more information, view the blog post [here](https://meraki.cisco.com/blog/2017/01/instant-systems-manager-free-30-day-trials/) or contact your Meraki sales rep.

Potential customers can manage 100 devices in order to try Meraki Systems Manager (the “SM Free 100”) at no cost. To be eligible for the SM Free 100, participants must:

* Provide valid information on the signup form, including your company email address
* Be directly employed by your company

SM Free 100 is only for internal use by your company. It is not for resale, distribution or service bureau use.

**Limit one SM Free 100 per organization and per individual.**

Your use of Systems Manager is governed by our [End Customer Agreement](https://meraki.cisco.com/support/policies#end-customer-agreement). By accepting the SM Free 100 you represent that you are authorized by your employer to accept the SM Free 100 and that you will disclose receipt of the SM Free 100 to your employer as and if required. Notwithstanding the End Customer Agreement, Cisco Meraki may terminate the Free 100 program at any time, including managing up to 100 devices at no cost – but if we do that, we’ll give you plenty of notice. The recipient is responsible for taxes and duties, if any. Please contact your Cisco Meraki rep if you have any questions.

* COMPANY

* PARTNERS

* GET STARTED

* RESOURCES

© 2024 Cisco Systems, Inc.

You are about to leave the US Meraki site...

Don't Leave

OK, Leave Site
